Adam Kenneweg

2B Computer Science | akenneweg@uwaterloo.ca akenneweg.com | github.com/akenne

SUMMARY

I am a full-stack developer, a learning enthusiast, and a programming addict. I have a wide array of interests and skills, with a tendency towards the backend. I enjoy development on both sides of the spectrum because it keeps me focused on efficiency and the user experience. I am pursuing a Computer Science degree at the University of Waterloo.

EXPERIENCE

PITSTOP

Backend Engineer

Jan 2016 - April 2016 | Velocity Garage, Waterloo, ON

- Lead development of team of 3 to create a backend from scratch using **Parse** and **Backbone.js**
- Replaced Parse with a **REST API** built with **Node.js** & **Express.js**, using **PostgreSQL**, hosted on **AWS**. Implemented full test suite using **Jenkins** & **Jira**
- Used Ruby on rails to create a Heroku app for live data analysis

GYMNATIK

Full-Stack Developer

Feb 2016 - April 2016

- Cofounded company and did all technical work. Designed and developed the working website, and created a backend using **Node.js** and **MongoDB**
- Passed it off to the business cofounder, who works on it independently now. He received **25k** of funding from a local angel investor

MARTELLO TECHNOLOGIES

Software Developer

May 2015 - Aug 2015 | Ottawa, ON

- Built a data warehousing system that generates \$1.2 million a year in revenue
- Developed system using multiple retrieval methods including **REST** calls, FTP servers, web scraping, and **SQL** queries
- Implemented system in Java, with the Spring Framework to extract, transform, and load data into PostgreSQL

PROJECTS

SPIDERCRAWLER

Oct 2014 - March 2015

Used **Python** to create a desktop program to crawl Steam's API to find users with valuable items. Involved processing large amounts of **JSON** data, and **multi-threading**. The program received **1000+** downloads after release.

WATISFOOD

Sept 2014

Created **Android** app during **HackTheNorth** with no prior experience. Provides info about food on campus using the school's API. A custom map is displayed showing all currently available food, with filters for preference.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Backend:

Python • Ruby • Node.js

Java • C++ • C

Frontend:

JavaScript • CSS • HTML5

TECHNOLOGIES

Frameworks:

Backbone.js • AngularJS • Express.js

Django • Rails

Spring Framework • Hibernate

Databases:

PostgreSQL • MongoDB

JDBC • Liquibase • Firebase

Other:

AWS • Heroku • Parse

Git • Android • Maven

Mockito • JUnit • Jira • Jenkins

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Bachelor of Computer Science Expected April 2019

AWARDS

President's Scholarship County of Simcoe Bursary

INTERESTS

Big Data
Artificial Intelligence
Machine Learning
Hiking
Photography
Travel
Cooking